Hey everyone, today we're going to be
talking about the brand new
encoder page in Blackout 2.4.
Now this is a big update for us. We
debuted at Cinegear and as
you probably already know,
we also launched the Astera integration.
I'm not going to cover that
here because Jeff made a great
full walkthrough, so check his video out.
The link will be in the
description. Today I'm going
to be talking about the other feature we
introduced, which is the brand new
encoder page and Stream Deck
integration. So we're here in Blackout
and you'll see down at the
bottom I have the brand new
encoders tab. The encoder tab is
available if you've
purchased the MIDI upgrade, which is
available for both our subscription users
and our perpetual license
users as an additional add-on.
So once you've purchased the MIDI add-on,
you'll see your encoder
tab down here at the bottom.
I can click on it and I'm taken to this
blank encoder page. And here
you can set up per parameter
encoder so you can grab one fixture or
multiple fixtures and adjust
the same parameter on all of
them. So here's how to set that up. I can
come up here and click
edit and you'll see all the
encoders change and allow me to pick
their parameter. So I'll
come over here to the first
one and make this intensity. I'll come
over to this one and
make a color temperature.
I'll come over to this one. I'll make it
crossfade and I'll come over
to this one and make it tint.
That's all I need for now. So I'll go
ahead and click save.
And if you look at the top, we also have
pages in our encoders tab,
just like in the faders tab.
So here you can have up to a hundred
available encoders. If I click in the
center of an encoder,
I can change it from fine, super fine and
coarse. Definitely like to
keep color temperature on
coarse. So you can select different
adjustment levels for
different encoders. At the bottom,
you can send an encoder to its minimum,
its maximum, and its home. And of course,
all of these buttons are MIDI learnable.
Pro tip, but you can
actually MIDI learn the
MIDI learn button. So it makes mapping
out your encoders even
faster because with the click of a
button, I can be in MIDI learn mode. To
set that up, go into link
status, connect to device,
and click MIDI learn. And you'll see I
can click MIDI learn again to map it.
I have it mapped to my stream deck, which
I'll show you in a minute.
So now that I'm in MIDI learn,
all I have to do is click on an encoder.
And then I just have to
twist an infinite encoder on my
MIDI device that I want to map there. If
I click in the center, I
can map the adjustment level,
as well as the minimum, home, and max
buttons. Now back in the
fixture page, all I have to do
is grab a bunch of fixtures. And as I
move the encoder, the
intensity changes. Of course,
this works for tint and color
temperature. You'll also see
at the top of each encoder,
it gives you a readout of the level you
set. So that's the encoder
page. Let's check out this
other tab for our stream deck. Stream
decks come with a USB A plug.
So you'll need a hub that has
a USB A port to plug into your iPad. The
first time you connect
your stream deck, you'll need
to go to the app store and you'll need to
download SD connect. All you
have to do is open the app and
follow the prompts. And then once you've
set that up, you just need to keep SD
connect on your iPad
and you never have to do anything with it
again. You never have to
open it again. You just have to
allow the permissions once and then
you're done. Now back in
blackout in the stream deck page,
this is where we can configure how the
buttons look right in
blackout. So you'll see, I already
have mine set up, but you can just click
on a button. You can change the
background to any color
you want. You can click here and change
it to an icon and you
can even give icons colors.
So I don't know, make that blue. And then
down here you can change the text.
And then up here you
can change the text color.
Once you've set up the appearance of the
buttons the way you want,
all you have to do is press
midi learn and learn the buttons to
whatever you want them to
correspond to. So here I can click
a macro and learn it right to the stream
deck. Coming soon are
stream deck pages and support
for different models of stream deck.
That's pretty much it. Not a lot of
explaining to do because
it's so intuitive and easy to set up the
stream deck and your
encoders page. If you like using
hardware with blackout, you're going to
love this update. As always,
let me know in the comments
what you want to see more of
and I'll see you next time.